#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/cynthianguyen-55822866 (LinkedIn)

# Top Skills

Data Analytics
Data Analysis
Statistics

#### Certifications

Certificate of Completion: Python Course

# Cynthia Nguyen

Founding Partner at Strategic AI (formerly AI Revolution)
Denver, Colorado, United States

# Summary

Al Technology expert building Al algorithms and solutions to integrate into value-generating business solutions. Over nine years of data science, statistics, Big Data, and Al design experience to build voice, text, geolocation, and image deeplearning Al algorithms. Computational and modeling expertise for fast data integration and software design into existing hardware systems. Founder of Al Revolution.

# Experience

Strategic AI, LLC Founding Partner June 2019 - Present (3 years 11 months) Denver, Colorado, United States

Big Data and AI design and integration

Al Revolution CEO/Co-founder June 2019 - Present (3 years 11 months) Denver, Colorado

Al Revolution has a goal of becoming the first Al Factory. We offer data management, bots, machine learning, recommendation systems, and recommendation chatbots to rent, lease, or outright buy for your business.

Independent Consultant
Data Scientist/Big Data Consultant
January 2018 - Present (5 years 4 months)
Greater Denver Area

Independent Data Scientist/Big Data Consultant specializing in healthcare, finance, and technology industries. Eight years of experience handling Big Data for advanced machine learning and mathematical analyses. Knowledge and experience with NLP, ensemble models, multivariate statistics, and complex network model flows research and analysis.

# Experfy Data Science Consultant May 2015 - Present (8 years)

Self-employed data consultant for multiple businesses of varying sizes around the world which need statistical modeling, advanced data analysis, and Business Intelligence set up and system integration.

- \* Multivariate analysis to design a machine learning model for Bayer Pharmaceutical's Marketing division to build a customer loyalty campaign that has 86% accuracy using R and SAS SQL.
- \* Nevada dental franchise data system set up and customer satisfaction statistical analysis using R and Stata.
- \* Building a machine learning model with multivariate logistic regression model to predict distribution channel efficiency for Rosetta Stone with 95% confidence in R and Stata.

### Cigna

Business Analyst Manager August 2018 - June 2019 (11 months)

Greater Denver Area

Responsible for automation of Big Data quality checks and advance analytics.

Public Service Credit Union
Data Scientist
July 2017 - December 2017 (6 months)
Lone Tree, Colorado

# Visa Data Scientist January 2017 - July 2017 (7 months)

Greater Denver Area

Microsoft
Data Scientist
2016 - 2016 (less than a year)

Verisk Health
Financial [Data] Analyst II
April 2013 - December 2014 (1 year 9 months)
Draper, UT

Monthly financial data analysis and modeling of millions of rows of healthcare transactional data for corporate invoicing and client problem resolution.

- \* Working with CFO and company directors to investigate financial errors in Oracle database and prepare error free reports for monthly invoicing.
- \* Providing clear communication across technical and non-technical audiences to build new business technology reporting platforms in Oracle Business Intelligence Enterprise Edition.

### Sunoptics

Business Analyst Consultant November 2012 - December 2012 (2 months)

Salt Lake City, UT

- \* Started up Analytics Department for international company with direct reporting access to CEO, CFO, COO, and built problem solving solutions across three departments.
- \* Initiated revenue analysis for largest six clients whose sales were responsible for 98% of revenue totaling \$20 million annually.
- \* Built performance dashboards for executive management and advised on technology investment decisions that helped the company save \$20K dollars in one month.
- \* Extensive cleanup of two million rows of data each week in order to reorganize into useful information and provide analysis for executive decision-making.

The Modellers Statistician Intern July 2012 - September 2012 (3 months) Salt Lake City, UT

- \* Building, designing, and programming marketing models of consumer behavior in SQL and SAS to provide recommendations for decision-making.
- \* Creating pricing models, clinical trials, and advanced analytics to guide business decisionmaking for nationally recognized technology companies, pharmaceutical companies, and commodity producer.
- \* Program VBA in Excel using Countif, Count, Index, Match, and others to create dashboards for easy interpretation and decision-making.

Fidelity Investments
Sr. Retail Trader/Helpdesk
December 2005 - September 2008 (2 years 10 months)
Salt Lake City, UT

- \* Conduct data analysis by means of basic skills in statistics using Excel.
- \* Calculate P&L, margin, explain financial risks, and other tasks to manage financial plan for Fidelity's retail customers.
- \* Discuss financial products in detail such as credit cards, interest rates, CDs, bonds, and other banking transactions.
- \* Find solutions for customers by coordinating tasks among Sales, Operations, and other departments.

# Education

University of Utah

Master of Science (M.S.), Statistics-Econometrics · (2010 - 2013)

University of Utah - David Eccles School of Business Master of Science (M.S.), Finance, General · (2007 - 2009)

University of Utah

Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Finance, General · (2002 - 2006)